Ubaldo Martinez III

18102 Talavera Ridge, Apt 2329, San Antonio, TX • +1 210-500-4599

• ubaldomartineziii@icloud.com • <u>aithub.com/um3dev</u>

Data Analyst Entry Level

Dynamic professional with a track record of enhancing company online presence through trend monitoring, new media adoption, and real-time insights. Empowers team members for effective outreach, resulting in a 20% engagement boost in just 6 months. Proven in configuring branded experiences on leading platforms, with a consistent focus on advancing organizational goals.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Verizon • San Antonio, TX, USA • Full-time • 07/2022 - 09/2023

Customer Service Representative - 40 Hours/Week

- Monitored relevant news, conversations, and trends in mobile device communication and social media platforms for 12 months.
- Empowered team members to take ownership of customer value initiatives and inside sales, resulting in a 10% increase in self-directed, value-adding actions over 6 months.
- Increased user engagement on slack platform by 30% in 6 months, leveraging emerging technologies.
- Analyzed and understood channel functions within the Consumer Group, including systems, tools, products, and call handling processes, facilitating better alignment with business strategies.
- Improved online visibility of knowledgebase materials by making suggestions to instruction workflow, resulting in a 20% increase in user engagement in 3 months.

Lil Brains Ltd • Austin, TX, USA • Full-time • 03/2019 - 06/2022

Full Stack Blockchain Developer - 40 Hours/Week

- Provided regular reports that highlighted emerging trends and opportunities, resulting in a 20% increase in a project's online engagement.
- Assisted in educating team members on the incorporation of social media techniques into communications and outreach activities.
- Increased social media engagement by 25% within 9 months, leveraging emerging technologies and analytics.

Apple • Austin, TX, USA • Full-time • 08/2015 - 02/2019

Senior Technical Support Advisor - 40 Hours/Week

- Increased online presence by 50% in six months through social media implementation and strategic content creation.
- Increased website traffic by 25% within 2 months through social media campaigns and use
 of emerging technologies.

• Improved reach of customer online services by establishing, configuring, and customizing new media/mobile instances in 6 months, utilizing social media and emerging technologies.

EDUCATION

Master Of Science M.S. Data Analytics

Western Governors University • 08/2023

Bachelor Of Science B.S. Information Technology

Western Governors University • 08/2017

CERTIFICATIONS

Project+

SAS Certified Specialist

Linux+

SKILLS

Brand Experience, Communication Skills, Conduct Research, Coordinating, Customer Engagement, Customer Satisfaction, Documentation, Effectiveness, Emerging Technologies, Emerging Trends, Integrated Marketing, Leadership, Mentorship, Mobile Devices, Monitoring, Negotiate, Online Communication, Operations, Performance Analysis, Planning, Prepare Reports, Program Analysis, Project Management, Provide Recommendations, Reporting, Research, Strategy, Target Marketing, Tracking System, Trends, Web Design, Writing